<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</title>
    <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Software Shepards</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 23:46:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>leadership is counter intuitive</title>
      <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/post/my-first-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 23:46:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/post/my-first-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/EscapeVelocity/img/scrubs-my-first-day.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My First Day, Scrubs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a dev and then as a manager, I grew up in a &amp;ldquo;startup environment&amp;rdquo;.  It was chaotic at times, but we were a team and we were in it together.  I was fortunate to lead this team but at the time, &amp;ldquo;lead&amp;rdquo; felt overstated.  I would nudge gently at points, define simple structures so we could track work and status, but mostly we had lots of high performing individuals and I just got out of their way.  Fast forward a couple of years and I had moved on.  I had taken a job as a developer on a small team at an insurance company and, within a year, was presented with an opportunity to lead the team and double its size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been a dev at Insurance Corp for a year, but when I walked in that first day as Lead, even though it was the same office, the same chair, and the same building, it felt brand new and I felt lost.  To make matters worse, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t technically asked to lead the team&amp;hellip; the former leader had an opportunity, he took it, and everyone just &amp;ldquo;assumed&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d pickup the reigns since, I assume, on paper at least, I had lead a team previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started asking myself, &amp;ldquo;what does &amp;lsquo;lead&amp;rsquo; even mean?&amp;rdquo;  I went from leading a team of high performing, self-directed individuals at Startup to a world of Project Managers, Project Management Office RACI/RAID/RAG reports, and &lt;em&gt;shudders&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip; Microsoft Project gantt charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could I ever have influence here?  And more importantly, how would I ever be able create an environment where we can achieve the same productivity as Startup?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had come to a pivotal point in my career that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t become obvious until years later.  In this moment, as an unknown quantity charged with leading a team in a &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; company, I decided to stubbornly (and maybe selfishly) stick to what I knew: how we did things at Startup.  And while I respected that people got value out of a lot of the existing processes and paperwork, I wanted something different.  I wanted to create an environment- a bubble- in Insurance Corp where my team could thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can too.  Practical leadership is not about grand speeches or having the authority to take a single action that acutely changes course; it&amp;rsquo;s in the banality of every day.  No one conversation or meeting is make or break, but daily we come to small forks in the road, and in aggregate the directions we pick can have a profound impact.  In what follows I&amp;rsquo;ll share examples and concrete, practical advice for forking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there I was, leader-by-default, and I figured what do I have to lose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leaders-shape-the-environment-not-the-people&#34;&gt;Leaders Shape The Environment.  Not the People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my first initial acts as Leader was seizing an opportunity I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass up.  We had an analyst who wanted to grow into a development role.  Let&amp;rsquo;s call her Sarah.  The icing on the cake?  Sarah was a SME on our core underwriting platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah approached me about the open headcount on the dev team and she asked me an interesting question.  Our conversation went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;S: &amp;ldquo;what do I need to do to become a developer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F: &amp;ldquo;The best thing you can do is write some code.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; what language?  Should it be a web app?  What do you expect&amp;hellip;. What do you want to SEE?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What I want to see is that you want to become a developer.  Pick a problem you have and solve it with code.  I don&amp;rsquo;t care how.  &lt;strong&gt;What I do care is that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; care.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt like I was speaking a different language.  It turns out, at Insurance Corp, it was common to find people dictating your every task.  The idea of giving someone autonomy in their decision making, even for a self-described &amp;ldquo;flat&amp;rdquo; organization like ours, was radical.  Now to be clear, I offered any help she needed on the technical end (syntax, advice, debugging), but the idea of self directing her own project seemed foreign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this a lot.  Too many people are trained to simply do what they are told.  When I&amp;rsquo;ve been managed, I am the person most informed about any given problem I&amp;rsquo;m facing.  &lt;strong&gt;I want my manager to tell me &lt;em&gt;what they want&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;how to do it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;  A specific technology or web stack isn&amp;rsquo;t going to tell me if you can program, you programming will tell me if you can program.  Why not write something that you can take ownership of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah created her project and it felt great to watch her demo it.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t care so much that she did it a particular way, I cared much more that she &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to do it: she took the opportunity to better herself in the interest of furthering her career.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wdzHgN7_Hs8&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good leaders give their team autonomy, mastery, and purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I had my first hire.  She would start off in a testing role so we could leverage her subject matter expertise, and she would be free to pair with anyone on the team to learn more about what we did and how.  That seemed like a great win-win.  I wanted product expertise, industry expertise, and shortened feedback loops.  Sarah wanted a different opportunity and dev experience.  This immediately gave our team more control over our work product - more autonomy than any previous dev team at Insurance Corp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that turned out to be a mistake.  Since she was now titled a tester, I was being pressured to have her report to our Test Manager.  And since I was the Dev Manager, that just didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to some at Insurance Corp.  This would be bad for our team for several reasons.  We had resource &amp;ldquo;pools&amp;rdquo; (BA&amp;rsquo;s, Devs, Testers, etc) and they would be moved by PM&amp;rsquo;s from project to project as necessary.  This meant Sarah wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be dedicated to our team.  It also meant I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have influence over her career development- her training, whether she could spend time with developers, giving her time to write automated tests (a great bridge from test to dev!).  Having a tester embedded with a dev team seemed so obvious to me, but looking around at my manager peers, I was left feeling like “to see what is in front of one’s nose needs a constant struggle.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/20283-to-see-what-is-in-front-of-one-s-nose-needs&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had nothing left to lose and &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; had a manager who had the right combination of desire to empower his people and lack of knowledge on how to structure or run a dev team.  We talked, and either my points had some measure of rationality or I had enough political capital as lead-as-default.  Either way, we got to keep Sarah on the team.  An obvious win-win, but without the effort in shaping the environment, we&amp;rsquo;d be worse off as a team.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;rsquo;{could be a crucial convo link here}&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, possibly my most memorable conversation with a PM ever.  Fast forward a couple of weeks, we have a prospective dev hire, Sarah is transitioning on to the team, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for my first catchup with our PM, Mary.  Mary had a list of questions that I had expected of the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s your team working on now/next?&amp;rdquo; variety, but there was one that threw me for a loop:&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;rsquo;{what format do you expect your requirements in was other question- good for autonomy point}&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What work have you assigned Sarah?  (And if it&amp;rsquo;s none, she would assign some or move Sarah to the aforementioned test team)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just remember panicking.  The expectation being set here was that if I was a competent manager, I should be able to predict her workload, assign it, and accurately allocate her time to keep her busy for the length of our iteration- basically the environment Sarah had just left.  I took a deep breath and in my most diplomatic voice simply stated &amp;ldquo;well I think that&amp;rsquo;s hard to predict since she&amp;rsquo;ll be accepting work as we complete it.  But if we organize ourselves so that our completed dev work is her todo list, we&amp;rsquo;ll constantly feed her work.&amp;rdquo;  If she had down time, well she wanted to grow into a development role; I would expect her to use the opportunity for watching a Pluralsight video, or walking through a tutorial, or pairing with a dev.  I was met with a deer-in-the-headlights look.  I felt as if I had said gravity didn&amp;rsquo;t work any more.  She politely nodded and I think out of nothing else than the sheer fact that Sarah &amp;ldquo;reported to me&amp;rdquo;, she was content to drop the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{this might be an overall conclusion}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leaders shape their environment.  They work to put people in roles that let them flourish, they give them autonomy, mastery, and purpose.  They move authority to the people with the information to make the best decision.  And, in my opinion, they are not afraid to disrupt the system from within by gently nudging influencers over a series of conversations in a tactic I like to refer to as Management Chess.  It was radical that I had a tester &amp;ldquo;reporting&amp;rdquo; to me, but because I had forged positive relationships with the people I would need to support this move, we started building what others would later recognize to be a high performing team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no specific moment, no speech, not even any explicit decision on my part, but in each of these decisions I was determined to do what I thought was right - to defy the tyranny of precedent&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/c/clarabarto276761.html&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and either we&amp;rsquo;re going to do something really special or I&amp;rsquo;d end up right back where I started which I was ok with.  So why not shoot for the moon?  At first, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure this was going to work, but the pride and the passion I saw during Sarah&amp;rsquo;s demo let me know we were on to something special.  I saw stiffled potential in people like her and that really bugged me.  So armed with some unproven ideas and some inspirational quotes to steer myself, I set out to make this an environment where we could bring out the best in our team, a place where you &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t ask yourself what the world needs. Ask yourself what makes you come alive and then go do that. Because what the world needs is people who have come alive.&amp;rdquo; &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/6273-don-t-ask-what-the-world-needs-ask-what-makes-you&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaders fix the environment (not the people)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaders make people think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaders push authority to information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leaders make people feel safe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 16:01:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re interested in helping to address a gap in our industry: communication.  Specifically, engaging internal &amp;amp; external customers in productive conversations, soliciting accurate insight into what they want, and being able to accurately, empathetically, and simply communicate back status from our technical teams.  We want to contribute to the technical community ideas, process, and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve worked in and for organizations that feel as if they are throwing money &amp;ldquo;into a black hole&amp;rdquo; and in return get back inaccurate, over budget projects.  The customers have given up their time to provide what they consider straight forward requests, have been open and responsive to questions, management has a schedule and a plan, and the developers are doing some of their best work delivering on features that they believe will make people happy- so &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/digital-mckinsey/our-insights/delivering-large-scale-it-projects-on-time-on-budget-and-on-value&#34;&gt;why do so many software projects fail&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fred&#34;&gt;Fred&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, I have lead teams recognized as examples of both technical leadership and team dynamics.  The technical magic happens when we leverage solid architecture and delivery practices to produce apps that elicit praise from our users for design and usability.  But we win true advocacy when we can take pride in being helpful and responsive to our users throughout delivery: from concept design to support- and back again.  I’ve achieved success on all these fronts and with multiple teams through the development of both the individual and the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer, you do not put yourself through 4 years of linked-lists and data structures, or teach yourself some foreign language an-hour-a-night, if you do not absolutely fawn over this stuff.  I think I do myself and my team a disservice as a manager if I’m not at the top of my game as a developer, and vice-versa: if we’re not organized and structured to continually deliver value, I get frustrated as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s damn fun to create. And it’s even more fun when requirements, process, and success are clearly defined: this is my objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ken&#34;&gt;Ken&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am passionate about delivering software and enjoy the challenges of mentoring and leading people.  When we have the right team members in the right roles, a shared purpose, and an appetite for taking risks and adapting to change, we deliver the most value.  Effective teams outperform individually talented people and have a more fulfilling work experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I here?  Probably for the same reasons you are reading this.  I am looking to be better at what I do and highlight what has worked for me and what hasn’t.  I want to improve how I communicate my ideas and this seemed like a great way to get exposure to a wider audience and hopefully help people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>welcome</title>
      <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 17:45:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spicy jalapeno bacon ipsum dolor amet ball tip andouille cupim chuck, tail short loin ground round shankle filet mignon meatball frankfurter shank. Cupim beef ribs leberkas, frankfurter sirloin shank ground round chuck pork belly. Pork loin pork chop shankle ball tip. Pork loin chuck pancetta short loin beef ham andouille brisket porchetta. Jowl brisket hamburger picanha, pig turkey tenderloin pork belly cupim capicola ball tip flank landjaeger corned beef andouille. Ribeye filet mignon turkey pastrami meatball jowl. Pancetta drumstick turkey ground round, short loin kevin sirloin shankle tail capicola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jowl prosciutto salami chicken. Tail chicken tongue jerky flank rump beef cupim burgdoggen. Shank shankle turkey burgdoggen, pork loin cupim kevin. Leberkas tenderloin beef frankfurter, hamburger t-bone pork belly bresaola. Alcatra sirloin ham flank boudin pancetta, doner t-bone bresaola chicken picanha meatball pork belly ball tip porchetta. Tri-tip shank venison bresaola kielbasa jowl pig shoulder boudin rump chicken cow sausage swine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>