<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</title>
    <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/tags/fred/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Software Shepards</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/tags/fred/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 16:01:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re interested in helping to address a gap in our industry: communication.  Specifically, engaging internal &amp;amp; external customers in productive conversations, soliciting accurate insight into what they want, and being able to accurately, empathetically, and simply communicate back status from our technical teams.  We want to contribute to the technical community ideas, process, and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve worked in and for organizations that feel as if they are throwing money &amp;ldquo;into a black hole&amp;rdquo; and in return get back inaccurate, over budget projects.  The customers have given up their time to provide what they consider straight forward requests, have been open and responsive to questions, management has a schedule and a plan, and the developers are doing some of their best work delivering on features that they believe will make people happy- so &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/digital-mckinsey/our-insights/delivering-large-scale-it-projects-on-time-on-budget-and-on-value&#34;&gt;why do so many software projects fail&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fred&#34;&gt;Fred&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Fred, but you probably already knew that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, however as my proverbial beard has grayed, my interests have extended beyond development- first out of necessity, then out of something more interesting.  I discovered that writing code- let alone good code- isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our customers expect us the Right Thing &lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt; and that has different meanings to different people.  To our BA and our Devs, it means working with the users on the ground to ensure our idea of what they want is in fact what they want.  To our PM, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter it is, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s on time &amp;#9786;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strive to build things that bring value, but value is subjective and means different things to different people- herein lies one of software&amp;rsquo;s greatest challenges.  We achieve this in my experience in one of two ways.  Either we have many individual users we can A/B test or we have few, specific users and therefore need to work closely to provide a win-win.  That is, even if we build the Right Thing &lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt; exactly as requested and we deliver it on time, it won&amp;rsquo;t matter if the client or executive or business unit doesn&amp;rsquo;t get value for the money they&amp;rsquo;ve spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution, I believe, lies at the intersection of People, Process, and Technology, but it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to simply execute on this.  We buy-in, we need genuine intrinsic motivation, we need to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/53035-diplomacy-is-the-art-of-letting-someone-else-have-your&#34;&gt;let people have our own way&lt;/a&gt;.  It turns out writing software is straightforward- not easy, but straightforward: machines are predictable beings- difficult and picky, but predictable.  Humans require more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take all this and add to it the fact that software is pure thought-stuff running in a virtual environment.  If I ask a carpenter to build a custom cabinet, I can see the process, I can learn a lot about how well its crafted just by looking at it.  With software, how do we do that?  I think that&amp;rsquo;s where there&amp;rsquo;s an unfilled gap in our industry that posses some really interesting challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT in general and, depending on your industry, software development specifically, is all too often seen as a cost center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to change that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>