<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</title>
    <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/tags/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on 2 devs, 1 blog (change this later)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017 Software Shepards</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 16:01:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://softwareshepherds.github.io/EscapeVelocity/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re interested in helping to address a gap in our industry: communication.  Specifically, engaging internal &amp;amp; external customers in productive conversations, soliciting accurate insight into what they want, and being able to accurately, empathetically, and simply communicate back status from our technical teams.  We want to contribute to the technical community ideas, process, and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve worked in and for organizations that feel as if they are throwing money &amp;ldquo;into a black hole&amp;rdquo; and in return get back inaccurate, over budget projects.  The customers have given up their time to provide what they consider straight forward requests, have been open and responsive to questions, management has a schedule and a plan, and the developers are doing some of their best work delivering on features that they believe will make people happy- so &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/digital-mckinsey/our-insights/delivering-large-scale-it-projects-on-time-on-budget-and-on-value&#34;&gt;why do so many software projects fail&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fred&#34;&gt;Fred&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, I have lead teams recognized as examples of both technical leadership and team dynamics.  The technical magic happens when we leverage solid architecture and delivery practices to produce apps that elicit praise from our users for design and usability.  But we win true advocacy when we can take pride in being helpful and responsive to our users throughout delivery: from concept design to support- and back again.  I’ve achieved success on all these fronts and with multiple teams through the development of both the individual and the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer, you do not put yourself through 4 years of linked-lists and data structures, or teach yourself some foreign language an-hour-a-night, if you do not absolutely fawn over this stuff.  I think I do myself and my team a disservice as a manager if I’m not at the top of my game as a developer, and vice-versa: if we’re not organized and structured to continually deliver value, I get frustrated as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s damn fun to create. And it’s even more fun when requirements, process, and success are clearly defined: this is my objective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>